Thank you so much, Jensen,
for joining yet again
for our Build developer conference.
You were here a couple of years ago
and we had a chance
at that time to talk
about all the great innovation
you are bringing to our Azure
and how customers were going to benefit.
And in fact, in the last two years,
you have sort of continued to push
the real frontier of innovation.
And you and I have talked a lot
about how this may be, again, the golden age
of both silicon hardware systems,
software systems all coming together.
And one of the things
that I've really learned
so much from you in saying, look,
at the end of the day,
our joint goal is to be able to deliver
more intelligence to the world.
In some sense you can even say
it's tokens per dollar per watt.
That's, sort of, what ultimately
is going to help the world flourish.
And, so, I just wanted to be able to, maybe,
get your perspective on all of this.
Maybe starting, in fact, with the very start of
what has been our industry,
which is Moore's Law.
You're really taking this Moore's Law
and put it back on hyperdrive.
And maybe you want to speak to–
in fact, right behind me
is a signed GB200 from you,
and we are now just about putting that
into massive production. And so,
I just want you to talk a little bit about
how this is actually working
generation to generation in terms of just
the benefits of Moore's Law.
So excited to be here.
Satya, in fact, two years ago
we had just launched the largest
AI supercomputer in the world together
on Azure.
And then right now, as we speak,
we are in full production
with Grace Blackwell.
We are ramping and scaling
and building the largest
AI supercomputer in the world in Azure.
And so this is just an exciting, exciting time
literally two years later.
Well, during that time
we've innovated across the entire stack.
This is the big change
in how computing works now.
Instead of just the processor
running static software, if you will,
everything about the stack has changed.
And so, our processor has changed,
our NVLink has changed
so that we can scale up
to a much larger compute node,
it's liquid cooled,
the architecture is FP4 Tensor Core,
we now have the ability to connect
Grace and Blackwell
coherently over a super fast link.
Very important in the world of
KV caching as we talk about these large
agentic model and agentic workloads.
And so all of this stuff
combined with our new CUDA
algorithms and new model technology
in your new AI infrastructure on Azure,
together, all of that together,
40x speed-up,
over Hopper.
40x speed-up over Hopper.
That's just an insane
speed-up in just two years.
It's just unbelievable.
And in fact, you know,
that type of compounding of S-curves,
your innovation, our innovation
coming together, ultimately driving
that frontier forward is just unbelievable.
But one of the other things
you taught me,
which I'll always remember,
is that speed of light
execution between even
the two organizations
is a way to deliver that.
Which is, there is, in fact,
you know, in our fleet,
as you can imagine,
we have all the generations of NVIDIA
and the new generations coming in.
And, do you want to speak to a little bit of what
Moore's Law and speed
have to do with each other
when it comes to driving innovation?
This is the insane execution
of our two organizations
now hyperlinked, if you will.
In fact,
when technology is moving
40 times per generation
and it's 40 times every two years,
you really want to upgrade every year.
You don't want to wait
every four years,
build out a giant fleet.
You want to build out small amounts
every single year.
And each year, let's say
it’s ten times faster than the last year,
and as a result, you,
you know, cost average,
if you will, or inverse to that,
performance average up your entire fleet.
And so you want to innovate
and you want to integrate
new data centers,
new computer architectures every year.
The complexity, of course,
is the work that you and I do
is not about building PCs anymore.
It's building these giant AI factories.
The scale is incredible.
The technology is insanely complicated.
And for our organizations now to be innovating
every single year requires
really tight integration.
And so that's the challenge
but the benefit’s incredible.
Yeah, and I think that that point
about that physics of the fleet, right?
Continuously
taking advantage of what comes out each year,
and that compounding of that
40x improvement every two years, let's say.
And then the fleet itself
will be there for four years,
five years,
and the benefits of it go all through that period.
In fact, talking about that,
one of the other things
you mentioned this even in, you know,
when you talked about the first point,
which is the software.
The innovation you're doing in CUDA,
some of the system software work
that we do end to end,
the app, where we talked a lot about even
the new app server for AI that we are doing.
Even something like even just,
you know, when I look at an application
and its performance,
whether it's latency, COGS,
even the smart techniques or prompt caching,
plus everything else that happens,
just makes a huge difference.
But you want to talk about
the compounding effects
of software that then add
to all of what we are doing together?
This is just incredible
about computing architectures
that are stable,
that are programmable,
have a rich ecosystem.
So, meanwhile while we're sitting here
executing from Pascal, to Ampere,
to Hopper, to Blackwell,
to you know, next generation,
all of our software architectures are compatible.
As a result, the rich ecosystem of tools
and all the developers
that are developing on it,
they're anxious to develop on it
because the install base is so large.
They're anxious to develop on it
because the ecosystem is so rich.
And all of that
enables them to invest deeply
into enhancing their models
and their algorithms
and their runtimes
and their orchestration layers,
because it affects
and benefits the entire fleet.
And so while we're sitting here
executing new generations
of architectures every single year,
we still want
architecture compatibility.
We want the rich ecosystem to be stable
so that software developers’ investments,
and all of the AI developers’ investments,
and all your infrastructure customers’ investments,
get to be distributed
and amortized across the entire fleet.
Yeah, and in fact, you know,
one of the things we're very excited about is,
given the fleet we now have,
we are able to take advantage
of these software advances
across the entire fleet.
And I think that's one of the things
that people don't understand,
that even the things that were shipped
from you multiple years ago
benefit from software advances.
That's right.
Continuously.
Hopper, we've been shipping
Hoppers to you now for two years.
Over the course of those two years,
through new algorithms,
let's just say Transformer
or let's just say Llama 70B.
Over the course of the last two years
we've improved the performance 40x.
Blackwell to Hoppers 40x,
Hopper on Hopper has been 40x
over the last two years.
We did that through all kinds of things like
in-flight batching,
and speculative decoding,
and all kinds of new algorithms
that sit underneath the inference engine.
And we're willing, of course,
all of the researchers
and all the developers,
they want to invest
in improving the architecture on CUDA
because they know
the install base is so large.
Whatever work that they do
will benefit a lot of the fleet
and many users will be able to benefit from it.
And so, you're willing to dedicate your entire–
you know, all of your heart and soul
into optimizing the algorithm and the architecture
because the install base is so large.
That's so well said because in some sense,
you know, the latest GB200 coming up
means some of the folks
who are doing the cutting edge
new training will go there.
And at the same time,
we are also providing, for example,
in Azure Container Service,
some of the sort of
software gains of the fleet on the GPU fleet
so that they can run any agent on it.
So that ability for us
to be able to flex the fleet
for the various different parts of the frontier
of latency, COGS, and performance
is just fantastic to have.
Yeah, your engineers and ours
are at this moment
optimizing runtimes on Ampere.
A10s, A100s.
And the beautiful thing is,
because of our natural understanding
of the importance of preserving, enhancing
developer productivity and developer value
for the life of the architecture,
we support software and
we fine tune software
for as long as we shall live.
And so,
That’s right. That’s right.
And all of that is just, between our two companies
we’re dedicated to all the developers.
Yeah, I know that's, absolutely.
And then the last one I wanted to unpack
is another thing you talk about,
sort of, GPUs is sort of more broader
than just one AI workload.
It is this accelerated compute vision
you've had, quite frankly,
for, you know, the longest time.
But I think that also is a
massive benefit to us
because that also means we can bring
many, many different classes of workloads.
That means customers can use this fleet,
for, of course, the cutting edge AI,
but many workloads.
But do you want to speak a little bit to the
what happens to utilization
and the diversity of workloads
that get all accelerated?
One of the benefits of CUDA
is that the install base is so large.
Another benefit of CUDA is that,
on the one hand,
it’s an accelerator architecture.
On the other hand,
it’s fairly general-purpose
for some of the heaviest workloads.
Our two teams are working on
accelerating data processing.
Accelerating data processing by 20x, 50x,
transcoding video,
image processing, models of all kinds,
recommender systems,
vector search engines.
All of those different types of algorithms
map wonderfully on top of CUDA.
And so with our computer scientists
working together,
we can accelerate
one workload after another workload,
after another workload.
And so as this tail,
if you will,
the long tail of GPUs
and all of the frontier models
move off to Blackwells and Futures,
we leave behind this compute fleet,
which is still
orders of magnitude
faster than general-purpose computing
that can be used
for all these different workloads.
And so our job
is to make sure that that fleet
and that workload,
all of the workloads of your data center,
are fully accelerated,
the fleet is fully utilized
for the entire life of the fleet.
No that's fantastic and so well captures
that real essence, right?
Ultimately, it's not just tokens
but it's all workloads,
per dollar per watt,
can we really accelerate them all
as we continue to innovate across
both the hardware
and the software boundaries
and really have the compounding effects
ultimately show up for our customers.
So thank you so much Jensen
for the partnership.
Thanks to everybody at NVIDIA
for the amazing work that you all are doing.
And it's great to see these two companies,
that have worked from the very beginning
on many of those architectures,
to come to this point
where there is complete new,
I would say, emergence
of computing that none of us
could have ever imagined,
but is, I think,
going to have a very profound impact.
So thank you again.
And Satya,
thank you for your partnership
and leadership,
and the alignment
between our two organizations
to build the most advanced
infrastructure in the world.
The most advanced
AI factories in the world,
is really a delight.
And here we are,
in just two years time,
AI has transformed so profoundly
and it's just so exciting.
This is the best of times
and the best of times are yet to come.
Thank you so much.